Prepare for the end.
End of Days is a action, horror, fantasy film directed by Peter Hyams.
Cynical bodyguard Jericho is hired by a man possessed by
Satan, who is in search of his bride.
When Jericho realizes what is happening, he must do
everything he can to save the woman and the world.
Jericho Cane, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
The Man, played by Gabriel Byrne.
Christine York, played by Robin Tunney.
Bobby Chicago, played by Kevin Pollak.
Detective Margie Francis, played by CCH Pounder.
Thomas Aquinas, played by Derrick O'Connor.
End of Days is a 1999 American action horror film directed
by Peter Hyams and written by Andrew W.
It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, with Gabriel Byrne, Robin Tunney, Kevin Pollak, Rod Steiger, CCH
Pounder, Derrick O'Connor, Miriam Margolyes, and Udo Kier in supporting roles.
The film follows former New York Police Department detective Jericho Cane (Schwarzenegger) who, after he saves a banker (Byrne) from an assassin, finds himself
embroiled in a religious conflict and must protect an innocent young woman (Tunney) who is chosen by evil forces to conceive the Antichrist with Satan.
The film was released by Universal Pictures in North America on November 24, 1999, and received
largely negative reviews, but was a box office success grossing $212 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of new year's eve, new york
city, nightmare, faith, christianity.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.